<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Async]]></title><description><![CDATA[A JavaScript meetup for Brighton & Hove]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com</link><generator>metalsmith-feed</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 15:44:10 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://asyncjs.com/feed/atom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Ask the Brains]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>And now for something a little different. This session, the content will be in your hands. Rather than having one speaker speaking on one topic, we&#39;ll be covering a range of topics chosen on the night, and leveraging the power of the mighty brains of Async to demystify, enlighten, and wax lyrical.</p>
<p>Inspired by the monthly <a href="http://brightonalt.net/">Brighton ALT.NET meetup</a> also hosted at the Skiff, we will be asking/talking/ranting about everything web related - 10 minutes per topic. The aim is to create a friendly environment for everyone to ask their &quot;that thing you&#39;ve never understood but always been too afraid to ask&quot; type questions, plus any other topics you feel like talking about on the night. Topics such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>Should I use Flow JS or TypeScript for my new app? Why?</li>
<li>I&#39;m new to development. Where do I get started?</li>
<li>I still don&#39;t get it! What the hell does &#39;this&#39; mean in Javascript?</li>
<li>How big do I let a project get before using Redux?</li>
<li>What actually is a database index anyway?</li>
<li>What VS Code plugins can you not live without?</li>
<li>Is it just me, or is React Router 4 rubbish?</li>
<li>Which Javascript unit testing framework should I use?</li>
</ul>
<p>The format works best when there is a diverse group of people and opinions in the room, so whether you consider yourself an absolute beginner, or a seasoned pro, please do come and join!</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/ask-the-brains</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/ask-the-brains</guid><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2257/3534516458_48e4e8595f_z_d.jpg</url><title>Question mark</title><link>https://www.flickr.com/photos/marcobellucci/3534516458</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Everyone ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Firebase]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>We&#39;ve all had that night where we get a great idea for a side project, and to make it really great it needs to have authentication, persistent state, some sort of backend to handle the stuff we can&#39;t expose to the frontend. If you think it&#39;s a really great idea you might even throw in some analytics.</p>
<p>You start off by looking at what&#39;s the ~cheapest~ best server you can spin up... is it a Droplet or a Dyno this month? Ubuntu or CentOS? Probably need some Docker or Chef to make sure you always redeploy it correctly. Now you can make a start on that Rest API... ah yeah Express, KOA? MongoDB connector, is Mongoose still a thing? Don&#39;t forget to set up those JWTs correctly.</p>
<p>At this point you&#39;re still having fun... who doesn&#39;t like building a clean, secure and well documented REST API and hitting it up with Postman (those automated testing features are amazing).</p>
<p>Seriously it&#39;s really rewarding to get all that set up and working, but by the time I get to the building the idea I&#39;m all funned out and it just becomes another directory in my projects folder.</p>
<p>Google&#39;s Firebase suite of tools get you up and running with <em>everything</em> in minutes, so you can focus on that awesome life changing idea.</p>
<p>Come down for a run down on the tools to get your web app up and running.</p>
<p><strong>Bring a laptop</strong> if you can, we&#39;ll be forming into teams to put your Firebase skills to the test in a chain reaction game to be the first team to send your rocket to Mars.</p>
<h3 id="about-the-speaker">About the speaker</h3>
<p>Harry is a Javascript developer at <a href="http://www.brandwatch.com">Brandwatch</a> who just loves all parts of development... but mostly frontend.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/firebase</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/firebase</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://firebase.google.com/_static/images/firebase/touchicon-180.png</url><title>Firebase logo</title><link>https://firebase.google.com/</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Harry Hogg ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ruby rocks]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Async has primarily been a JavaScript meetup since it was founded (back in 2010!). We can all learn a lot from looking at other languages though, and one of the more elegant web languages around is <a href="https://www.ruby-lang.org/en/">Ruby</a>. Luckily, our own <a href="https://twitter.com/notthepoint">Dot Wingrove</a> is a Rubyist and will be our guide. </p>
<p>This talk will teach you a bit about Ruby via the medium of rock-paper-scissors, plus a little bit about AI history. It will also make you laugh — at least a little. You&#39;ll also learn some game theory, some mind games, and finally, how to build a world champion bot in the universe of Rock Paper Scissors.</p>
<p>The talk is aimed at all developers even if they&#39;re new to Ruby, but anyone with some Ruby background should also find it interesting. All the examples in the talk and are explained step by step, and many of them relatively basic.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/ruby-rocks</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/ruby-rocks</guid><pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>/img/talks/ruby-logo.png</url><title>Ruby logo</title><link>https://www.ruby-lang.org/en/</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Dorothy Wingrove ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[2017 International Show n' Tell]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>What&#39;s that? November already? Crikey, time for another <strong>International Async Show&#39;n&#39;tell</strong>! Following on from last year&#39;s success, <a href="http://2017.ffconf.org/">ffconf 2017</a> will again be over two days, so to prevent clashing with the afterparties we&#39;ll be meeting <em>on Wednesday 8th November</em> - not Thursday. The International show&#39;n&#39;tell has become an institution in its own right, and is a perfect opportunity to give a peek at your passion project, try out a lightning talk, or just share what&#39;s on your mind.</p>
<p>And, <em>if you’d like to grab a speaking slot</em>, you’ll have five minutes on the night to tell us about something… a project, a library, a technique, a story, or anything else about JavaScript, related tech (HTML, CSS, SVG, etc), or the wider world of web. We hope to bring together a blend of local projects with those from travellers to England for the conference.</p>
<p>Speakers, please <a data-gist href="https://gist.github.com/larister/f079111663031d4db0339f8e3f12b55f">add a comment to the Speakers&#39; Gist</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Please Note</strong>: This year, the venue has changed, and will now be at <a href="https://www.theskiff.org/">The Skiff</a>. See there me hearties.</p>
<p>For a spot of inspiration, take a look at our International Show n&#39; Tells in <a href="https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2016/">2016</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-2015/">2015</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-2014/">2014</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-2013/">2013</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-2012/">2012</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/international2011/">2011</a> and <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell3/">2010</a>. We&#39;ve also hosted local show n&#39; tells: <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-spring-2016/">1</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-spring-2015/">2</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/birthday4/">3</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/birthday3/">4</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/birthday2/">5</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/birthday/">6</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell2/">7</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell/">8</a>.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2017</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2017</guid><pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8334/8388040402_96fc3bfa96_z_d.jpg</url><title>Jugglers</title><link>https://www.flickr.com/photos/risager/</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ All and sundry ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Code, Explore, Create. Inspirational Demos from codebar]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>For those who haven&#39;t heard of us, <a href="https://codebar.io/">codebar</a> is a non-profit initiative that facilitates the growth of a diverse tech community by running regular programming workshops. The atmosphere at each weekly codebar meeting is pretty special – a great mix of catching-up, idea sharing and learning. In addition to meeting weekly, we work hard to offer interesting and exciting events and workshops.</p>
<p>Come down for an upbeat evening of code demos, stories and inspiration sharing from our latest event; a <a href="http://brightondigitalfestival.co.uk/events/code-explore-create-day-1">whole</a> <a href="http://brightondigitalfestival.co.uk/events/code-explore-create-day-2">weekend</a> of creative coding, held as part of Brighton Digital Festival.
Everyone is welcome to come along. If you have ever thought about becoming a student or a coach at codebar, it’d be a great time to see what we do and ask us questions!</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/codebar-takeover</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/codebar-takeover</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>http://codebar.io/images/logo-square.png</url><title>Codebar Logo</title><link>https://codebar.io/brighton</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ The Codebar Brighton team ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Pathfinding with Snake: A Javascript Hacknight]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Pathfinding is a concept that we all encounter in our day to day lives. In software, like SatNavs planning the quickest route to a destination or utility companies installing infrastructure in the most efficient way possible. In our own brains, from a premeditated route to the train station or a split second decision of your next step to avoid a fellow pedestrian.</p>
<p>Each of these decisions have obstacles that must be avoided and have a certain cost associated with it, be it fuel, money, time etc... Pathfinding is the problem of finding the best path from a starting point to a goal, taking into account these factors.</p>
<p>Come down for a light hearted competitive game of writing your own pathfinding solutions using an online visual environment with the classic game of Snake.</p>
<p>Bring a laptop if you can, but we’ll be forming into teams so come along even if you don’t have access to one. All levels of coders are welcome, as the approach is just as important as the code itself.</p>
<h3 id="about-the-speaker">About the speaker</h3>
<p>Harry is a Javascript developer at <a href="www.brandwatch.com">Brandwatch</a>, who spends most of his time rolling around in React components and has an unhealthy love for CSS.</p>
<h2 id="update">Update</h2>
<p>This meeting will be sponsored by <a href="https://www.brandwatch.com/careers">Brandwatch</a>, who will provide pizzas and beers for all. Please get in touch if you have any specific dietary requirements at hello AT asyncjs DOT com.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/pathfinding-with-snake</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/pathfinding-with-snake</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>http://i.imgur.com/RmelSPs.png</url><title>Snake</title></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Harry Hogg ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Getting into the Flow: Static Types for Javascript]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Static type systems are all the rage these days.
Languages like Typescript, Elm, and Purescript,
use static types to reason about code without running it,
eliminating certain classes of bugs and making code easier to understand.</p>
<p>However, adopting a new programming language comes at a cost.
Wouldn&#39;t it be nice if we could benefit from static types
in our existing Javascript code
without jumping over to a new language?</p>
<p>Enter Facebook&#39;s <a href="https://github.com/facebook/flow">Flow</a>,
a static type checker for ordinary Javascript.
In this talk I&#39;ll show you how to add Flow
to an existing Javascript project.
I&#39;ll demonstrate how Flow&#39;s static types work and how
they&#39;ll help uncover bugs in your code.
Finally, I&#39;ll talk about how to adjust your programming style
to get the most benefit from static types.</p>
<h1 id="about-the-speaker">About the Speaker</h1>
<p>Dave is a Scala developer moonlighting as a Javascripter.
By day he works for Brighton-based Scala consultancy <a href="http://underscore.io">Underscore</a>
(no relation to the popular Javascript library).
He spends most of his time <a href="http://cartographer.io">writing software</a>,
<a href="http://underscore.io/books/">writing books about writing software</a>,
and <a href="http://meowsynth.com/">building synthesizers from the souls of tormented cats</a>.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/types-for-js</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/types-for-js</guid><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://static.pexels.com/photos/261626/pexels-photo-261626.jpeg</url><title>static typing</title><link>https://www.pexels.com/photo/alphabet-blur-close-up-font-261626/</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Dave Gurnell ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mapping with D3]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>For thousands of years humans have sought to understand the physical world through the making of maps, and that is as true today as it was all those millennia ago. Countless tools now exist to help with making maps and the JavaScript world is no exception, with several libraries that make it easier than ever to create and experiment with maps. One of those libraries is D3, which contains some powerful features for making beautiful interactive maps.</p>
<p>In this talk Peter Cook will show us the process of making maps using D3, starting with acquiring geographic data, converting it to GeoJSON, and rendering it using D3. Along the way he&#39;ll cover issues such as SVG vs. Canvas rendering, projections, choropleth maps and how to make a spinning globe with a few lines of JavaScript (and D3). Whether you&#39;re a JavaScript coder, or just someone who&#39;s interested in the current techniques for making maps, this is a talk no to be missed!</p>
<p><a href="http://animateddata.co.uk/">Peter Cook</a> is a freelance data visualisation designer and developer. He&#39;s the author of <a href="http://d3indepth.com/">D3 in Depth</a> and also runs the <a href="https://www.meetup.com/Data-Visualisation-Brighton/">Data Visualisation Brighton Meetup group</a>.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/d3-geo</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/d3-geo</guid><pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3602/3310737856_f50756c9a4_z_d.jpg</url><title>hot cup of globes</title><link>https://www.flickr.com/photos/mrgranito/3310737856/</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Peter Cook ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[GraphQL with Tom Ashworth]]></title><description><![CDATA[<h2 id="update-please-note-the-venue-change-we-will-be-returning-to-the-skiff-see-you-there-">UPDATE: Please note the venue change, we will be returning to The Skiff. See you there!</h2>
<p>This talk will see the long-awaited return of Tom Ashworth. </p>
<p>Tom will be introducing GraphQL - what it is, why it was created and why you&#39;d want to use it. He&#39;ll then cover how they introduced it at Twitter, from prototype to a production system getting adoption.</p>
<p>A basic knowledge of JavaScript is assumed.</p>
<p>Tom is a software engineer at Twitter. Before working on GraphQL, he was technical lead on the TweetDeck frontend team.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/graphql</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/graphql</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>http://i.imgur.com/ZPGkmGm.png</url><title>Twitter GraphQL logo</title></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Tom Ashworth ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Building an Internet-of-Things thing]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Internet of Things, Smart devices, Wearables, [insert smug buzzword here]. It&#39;s what all the cool kids are talking about so lets have a go at building one ourselves.
We&#39;re going to go over the very basics of designing a circuit, prototyping and producing a top quality PCB. The gadget we build will wirelessly connect to the outside world and become a part of the Internet of Things. </p>
<p>I&#39;m presuming no prior-knowledge of electronics.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/hardware-hacking</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/hardware-hacking</guid><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://i.imgur.com/LBjIg5i.jpg</url><title>Async motherboard</title><link>https://i.imgur.com/LBjIg5i.jpg</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Remi Shergold ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[From iFrame to ByeFrame]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>iFrames are a quick and easy way to put content on other people’s websites, but not without their many drawbacks. James and Andy, the front end team from StoryStream, explain how they replaced iFrames with plain old JavaScript to seamlessly inject content into any website in the world, and detail the challenges they overcame along the way.</p>
<p>We’ll be discussing our approach in some detail but you’ll only need a general knowledge of JavaScript, HTML and CSS to enjoy and understand it. Ideally, you’ll also dislike iFrames to develop with as much as we do.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/iframe-to-byeframe</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/iframe-to-byeframe</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://image.freepik.com/free-icon/code-optimization_318-49778.jpg</url><title>iframe</title><link>http://www.freepik.com/free-icon/code-optimization_736746.htm</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Andy Taylor, James Brannon ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Writing Secure JavaScript]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Some of the very things that make JavaScript awesome can also expose it to security risks. This talk will go through some sample security flaws unique to Node’s async nature and surrounding ecosystem (or especially relevant to it) and will show how these could occur in your own code or in npm dependencies.</p>
<p>The talk will revolve around a sample vulnerable application, <a href="https://github.com/Snyk/goof">Goof</a>, which I will exploit as an attacker would. For each issue, I&#39;ll explain why it happened, show its impact, and – most importantly – see how to avoid or fix it</p>
<hr>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/writing-secure-javascript</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/writing-secure-javascript</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/a/aa/Byseyhanla.jpg</url><title>Byseyhanla</title><link>https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Byseyhanla.jpg</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Josh Emerson ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[ESGolf (JavaScript Golf 2)]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Come for a night of writing code that should get you fired from any normal programming job. Have fun and maybe even learn some new things about JavaScript and programming. Hideous trousers not required (but highly encouraged).</p>
<p>This time you&#39;ll be able to use the full power of ES6/ES2015 so this is a great opportunity to learn about Fancy New JavaScript.</p>
<p>The rules are simple. Solve the challenge in as fewer (key)strokes as possible to win the game, the adulation of your peers, and maybe even a sweetie.</p>
<p>Bring a laptop if you can, but we’ll be forming into teams so come along even if you don’t have access to one. Or, if you really love a challenge, you could do it all in your head and draw up your answer on the whiteboard!</p>
<p>All levels of coder are welcome for an educational and entertaining evening. See you there!</p>
<hr>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/esgolf</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/esgolf</guid><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7379/12758383654_ab4b43d147_z_d.jpg</url><title>Urbanowicz_Krzysztof_GOLF</title><link>https://www.flickr.com/photos/kurbanowicz/12758383654/in/photolist-krq3XY-7hTRLz-9kGXLo-awf96H-9kGXTb-7hTSDX-7hXNAY-kroiT4-6xcLyT-65CWTR-5ds8DL-9kGYdb-9kDVyT-9a69ML-5bCwNN-efi4ma-56hckS-4kQ3Fv-eBP5xt-6QKY1E-c3HmpL-eBRqu3-4ZxP3p-5bCxDW-krpfTx-4ZC1qL-5bCB6j-3vs2Y1-4ZC1u5-4q64vn-4ZxM8Z-4ZxNwg-341zZd-6xj6oL-4ZxNUP-9L3STz-9L3SXt-dxM9tg-dbJjkc-anWVqa-4ZxNqz-5bym8g-4PXK7g-dbJkFS-5bxftP-5bym7V-krp6SB-5bCsCE-5t5bP2-5byh6a</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Tom Parslow ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[The rise of the bots]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>You&#39;ve surely heard of them, the bots are coming! Some predict they will cause the end of mobile applications, others that they will even take over jobs!</p>
<p>Throughout this talk, we will try to answer many questions about the rise of the bots: Who are they? Why such enthusiasm? Can they really take over the world of mobile applications?</p>
<p>The talk will also include a tutorial so you can start building your own bots on Facebook Messenger using api.ai and node.js! </p>
<h3 id="update">UPDATE</h3>
<p>Here are Alex&#39;s slides from the night: <a href="http://riseofthebots.webnicol.fr/">http://riseofthebots.webnicol.fr/</a></p>
<hr>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/how-to-build-a-bot</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/how-to-build-a-bot</guid><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>/images/talks/riseOfTheBots.jpg</url><title>Artificial Intelligence</title><link>https://pixabay.com/p-503588/?no_redirect</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Alexandre Nicol ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[What is Angular 2? From a simple component to zones]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Angular 2 is a complete rewrite of AngularJS (like a new language) and got to its full release of 2.0.0 in mid Sept 2016 after 2 years of going through alpha, beta and RC releases and has new bits added every week (now at 2.3.1 – 20/12/16).  Gordon Cumming is a Senior Angular/Angular 2 developer and has been studying Angular 2 for over 2 years although only started coding in Oct 2015. He lives and breathes Angular 2 on a daily basis (often 12 hours per day 7 days a week) and has written a 2000 page training application in Angular 2, all about Angular 2, with about 50 working applications within it to demonstrate different features.  This application has lots of show/hide sections so that the viewers don’t have too  much information on the screen at once.</p>
<p>Angular 2 is a complete framework (as is AngularJS) compared to ReactJS (only a library) and it has many more features, compared to these others.  It is complex due to its many parts, but on a basic level, easy to get things done (not difficult), once you’ve gone up a learning curve.  However there are of course more complex bits, which will take months or years of knowledge and experience to know about and master.  The number of times I’ve heard an expert? say “I hadn’t heard of that part of Angular 2 before!”  Some of these features will help improve the performance (load time or run time speed) or sometimes help reduce the size of your code (important for mobile devices).</p>
<p>In this talk Gordon will use slides and example coding to introduce you to Angular 2, show you what its main features are, compare it to AngularJS (Angular 1.x) and ReactJS, warn you about some pitfalls in learning Angular 2 and what the best way to get started with it is.  He will cover what it is, the main building blocks and features and how it caters for different platforms.</p>
<hr>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/intro-to-angular-2</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/intro-to-angular-2</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://www.ag-grid.com/images/angular2.png</url><title>Angular 2</title><link>https://angular.io/</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Gordon Cumming ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Web based interactive visualizations in D3.js]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>D3.js is a powerful JavaScript library for producing rich interactive data-driven visualizations for the web. The last few decades have seen an explosion of data; the challenge now is how to process and present that data in a human-readable way. As the plentiful examples at <a href="https://d3js.org">d3js.org</a> and <a href="https://bl.ocks.org">blocks.org</a> show, D3 is capable of some pretty impressive stuff! This talk assumes no previous knowledge of D3.JS but does assume basic familiarity with JavaScript or a similar programming language.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="about-the-speaker">About the speaker</h3>
<p>Tom Parslow is a freelance polyglot developer and cake enthusiast based in Brighton. He has worked on projects ranging from <a href="https://tomparslow.co.uk/technology/d3/#content">rich interactive data visualisations with D3</a> and cross <a href="https://tomparslow.co.uk/technology/react-native/#content">platform mobile applications with React Native</a> to <a href="https://tomparslow.co.uk/project/penaltyclick/#content">internet controlled football playing robots</a> and <a href="https://tomparslow.co.uk/project/colourcrush/#content">robotic photo booths</a>. You can check out his website at <a href="https://tomparslow.co.uk">tomparslow.co.uk</a> or follow him on Twitter at <a href="https://twitter.com/almostobsolete">@almostobsolete</a></p>
<h2 id="update-slides">Update: slides</h2>
<p>Tom&#39;s slides for the talk are available <a href="http://almostobsolete.net/talks/d3-asyncjs/">here</a></p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/intro-to-d3</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/intro-to-d3</guid><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://d3js.org/preview.png</url><title>D3 Preview</title><link>https://d3js.org/</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Tom Parslow ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[2016 International Show n' Tell]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Come one, come all, to the renowned annual <strong>International Async Show&#39;n&#39;tell</strong>! This year&#39;s <a href="http://2016.ffconf.org/">ffconf</a> will for the first time be over two days, so to prevent clashing with the afterparties, this year&#39;s Show&#39;n&#39;Tell will be <em>on Wednesday 9th November</em> - not Thursday. This special Async is for Brightonians and pilgrims alike to show us what&#39;s getting their juices flowing right now.</p>
<p>If you&#39;d like to attend, just <a href="http://lanyrd.com/2016/asyncjs-international-showntell">sign up on the Lanyrd event page</a>.</p>
<p>And, <em>if you’d like to grab a speaking slot</em>, you’ll have five minutes on the night to tell us about something… a project, a library, a technique, a story, or anything else about JavaScript, related tech (HTML, CSS, SVG, etc), or the wider world of web. We hope to bring together a blend of local projects with those from travellers to England for the conference.</p>
<p>Speakers, please <a data-gist href="https://gist.github.com/larister/2ffbbaa42e09a22b491bf7028ec47b02">add a comment to the Speakers&#39; Gist</a>.</p>
<p>For a spot of inspiration, take a look at our International Show n&#39; Tells in <a href="https://asyncjs.com/showntell-2015/">2015</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-2014/">2014</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-2013/">2013</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-2012/">2012</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/international2011/">2011</a> and <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell3/">2010</a>. We&#39;ve also hosted local show n&#39; tells: <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-spring-2016/">1</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-spring-2015/">2</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/birthday4/">3</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/birthday3/">4</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/birthday2/">5</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/birthday/">6</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell2/">7</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell/">8</a>.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2016</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2016</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/f/f4/One-man_band_street_performer_-_5.jpg</url><title>One man band street performer</title><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Street_performance</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Everyone ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Neural Networks for Squirrels]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>What do Neural Networks and JavaScript have in common? </p>
<p>Well, probably more than what you think! </p>
<p>They may be a  match made in the heaven, and we are going to see feel the influence of both in the coming years.</p>
<p>Neural Networks and JavaScript are today&#39;s buzzwords, but how can we use them together?</p>
<p>You will have an introduction about what Neural Networks are, how to apply them in your applications, which packages are available in the JS community and how to think in terms of architectures to solve complex problems.</p>
<p>Prerequisites:</p>
<ul>
<li>A smartphone, tablet or laptop (only if you want to have access to more insights during the presentation or to play with the provided demos)</li>
<li>Basic knowledge of JavaScript</li>
</ul>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/neural-networks</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/neural-networks</guid><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>/images/talks/neuralNetworksForSquirrels.jpg</url><title>Neural Networks for Squirrels</title></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Antonio De Luca ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Make Your Own JS Game Part 2]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Alvin Ourrad will return for another instalment of his workshops on how to Make Your Own JS Game. Don&#39;t worry if you missed <a href="https://asyncjs.com/make-your-own-js-game/">the first</a>, we&#39;ll provide you with the boilerplate to get you up to date. More details to follow...</p>
<hr>
<p>This meeting will be sponsored by <a href="https://www.brandwatch.com/careers">Brandwatch</a>, who will provide pizzas and beers for all. Please get in touch if you have any specific dietary requirements at hello AT asyncjs DOT com</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/make-your-own-js-game-pt-2</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/make-your-own-js-game-pt-2</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2016 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/2/26/Video_Game_Barnstar_Hires.png</url><title>Video Game Barnstar Hires</title><link>https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Video_Game_Barnstar_Hires.png</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Alvin Ourrad ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fishcotheque (part 2 of 2)]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Calling all designers, developers and anyone else with a nautical interest. Have you ever wondered what lives down below the pier?</p>
<p>For this year&#39;s Brighton Digital Festival, we&#39;re continuing with our <a href="https://asyncjs.com/playcanvas-hacknight-part-1/">tradition</a> <a href="https://asyncjs.com/robocode-hackathon-part-1/">of</a> <a href="https://asyncjs.com/jungle/">Hacknights</a>. This year we&#39;re creating a collaborative canvas of weird and wonderful animated sea creatures to live in our <em>Async Fishcotheque</em>.</p>
<p>If you are a coder, an artist, or just curious about what we&#39;re up to, then do sign up and come along to learn how to create your very own creature.</p>
<p>We&#39;re looking for talented artists to give our sea creatures some visual flair and to help create an interesting environment for them to live in. So even if programming isn&#39;t your thing, do please come along and join the fun.</p>
<p>Please bring a laptop if you can. But don&#39;t worry if you don&#39;t have one, people will be working in small groups so you can always pair up with somebody who does.</p>
<p>We&#39;ll post the fishcotheque online here for the world to see.</p>
<p>This is part 2 of a 2 part series.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/fishcotheque-part-2</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/fishcotheque-part-2</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>/images/talks/fishcotheque.jpg</url><title>Fishcotheque</title><link>/images/talks/fishcotheque.jpg</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Everybody ]]</author></item></channel></rss>